Muhammad Babar

Full Stack Developer (Bootstrap 5, Node JS, Angular 12, .NET Core API with GraphQL)

Phone: +966591802016

E-mail: <u>muhammadirfanbaber@gmail.com</u>

My Portfolio: http://www.ibabar.work

Career Objective

 \blacksquare

I enjoy positions that allow me to learn new technologies, and to work in an environment that fosters professional growth and continuous learning.

Personal Information

Name	Muhammad Babar
Iqama Profession	Computer Programmer
Date of Birth	23 rd March 1988
Iqama Status	Transferable
SEC Registration Expiry Date	DEC 2023

Educational Qualification ▼

Degree/Certificate	Year	Division/Grade	Discipline/Subject
BSCS (4 year)	2011	1 st / 77.5%	Computer Science

Professional Summary

- ▼
- **About 12** years of comprehensive experience in Software Development and Data Base Application.
- As a full developer, I am able to developer web applications fully from backend to front end.
- Using Angular 12 as front end and Node JS / .Net Core Web API as backend tool.
- Sound knowledge of Object-Oriented Software Engineering.
- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Well capable of developing Business Objects for Commercial Applications.
- Expert in Debugging and solution of problems of large and complex applications.
- Well experienced of enhancing facility in a large product according to client's need.

Skills

Technologies	Html 5 CSS 3 , Bootstrap 5, web font icons like font awesome 4.7. Angular 12 ,Node JS , .NET CORE 6 Api (monolith) , Micro services architecture, Rabbit MQ message Bus , Github version control , Graph query language , Apollo client, MVC, Repository pattern, unity of work, code first, database first. Chrome web browser Extensions. Asp.net, Telerik Controls, MVC kendo , SignalR for real time update , ADO, ADO.Net, excel sheets using .Net, XAML, XML, XML-Schema, X-Path, Window Service, Web Service, MSI Setup, ,web Api,QT Framework,
Visual Tools	C#, Mongo DB, pouchdb,SQL Server 2019, Visual Studion 2019, VS CODE, Saudi Mada Payment Integration, Authorized.net payment gateway. PayPal, Access control and biometric Api and SDK,
Reports tools	Stimulsoft web Reports , RDLC reports, Crystal, JQuery Charts , IRON Pdf
Others	Java Script, JQuery, TFS, SVN, Perforce, css3,html 5 , Biometric SDK and API , Com port programming

Work Experience

1. NOV 2018 to Present.

Dr. Sulaiman al Habib (cloud Solution), Saudi Arabia:

AL-Olaya, Riyadh. KSA.

https://www.cloudsolution-sa.com/

Designation: Full Stack Developer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Vital role in Outpatient / Inpatient and appointment modules.

Office Phone: +966 115 259000

2. Aug 2017 to 2018.

Al Rabie, Saudi Arabia: AL-Olaya, Riyadh. KSA. https://www.rabiahtech.com

Designation: Full Stack Developer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Research on software optimizations, Testing and maintenance of

various modules, Query optimizations, Reports optimization

Office Phone: +966 11 419 7707 Ext: 105

3. Aug 2016 to Aug 2017

CF4IT, Saudi Arabia:

4th Floor, Madina Tower, Madina Street, Al-Jubail. KSA.

https://www.cf4it.com

Designation: Sr. Software Engineer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Research on software optimizations, Testing and maintenance of

various modules, Query optimizations, Reports optimization

Office Phone:

4. Feb 2015 to July 2016

Emcentrix, Islamabad:

House# 159, Street 27, G-10/1, Islamabad

https://www.emcentrix.org

Designation: Sr. Software Engineer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Research on software optimizations, Testing and maintenance of

various modules, Query optimizations, Reports optimization

Office Phone:

5. Feb 2012 to Jan 2015

Flexoft, Islamabad:

House#819A, Street 11, I-8/2, Islamabad Designation: Software Engineer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Research on software optimizations, Testing of various modules,

Monitoring Web Service, maintaining window service and connector application.

Office Phone: 051-4864478

6. July 2011 to Feb 2012

Nimble Geeks, Islamabad:

House#51A, Street 26, F-10/1, Islamabad

www.Nimblegeeks.com

Designation: Jr. Software Engineer.

Responsibilities: Application designing and development, Query Optimization, Web designing, Testing of various modules.

Software Projects

▼

Home Health Care (HHC)

Description: Home Health Care aims at providing health care assistance and nursing services for patients in the comfort

of their homes. The home health care design to provide specialized health care services at the patient's

place of residence, as well as help the family in taking extra care of patients.

Technologies: Node JS , Angular , .NET CORE , GraphQL , MongoDB

Responsibilities: Build Node JS Api for mobile app (flutter), Angular 12. Worked on Appointment (walkin-in, call center, and

OPD) and patient Referral creation screen for Ministry of health (MOH).

2. CYCLUS (RCM & Digital Claim Management)

Description: A cloud-based solution covers all Revenue Cycle Management processes in order to improve collection

payment cycle and reduce claims decline rate.

• Enables healthcare providers to efficiently manage and submit Insurance claims.

• Data Loggin with Mongoose with Node JS.

• Complete claim-scrubbing process.

• Payers to review and accept or reject claims.

• Rule engine to validate for errors.

• Reporting engine based on GraphQL.

• Business intelligence.

• Architecture and application business flow.

• ICD-10 codes compliant.

• Australian Classification of Health Interventions implementation.

Technologies: Node JS, MongoDb, PoutchDb, Single Sign On, Angular 2, Rxjs, Core Apis with Graph QL along with Api

Gateway with micro services architecture. jenkins,

Responsibilities: worked as core developer on various application parts like User Access, billing and Claims with Naphies

Integration with CCHI and Bupa (others health provider).

WEB EMR / RRT (Rapid Response Team)

Description: RRT is a powerful complete Electronic Health Record (EHR), cloud native, web based, fully integrated

> Healthcare Information System. It is a comprehensive and rich functional Hospital information system designed to manage all aspects of a hospital operations such as medical, administrative, financial, legal and the corresponding service processing. It allows Physicians spend more time with patients, increases patient's safety and reduce medical errors by ensuring the timely availability of the right information at the right time

to the right person at the time of Care.

Technologies: Angular 12, .Net Core, mongoDB. Node JS

Responsibilities: Node JS Api for Data Driven .worked on OPD module, appointment, and outpatient various screens .

HROMS (Complete ERP Solution KSA)

Complete ERP solution consisting of finance, HR, payroll, Project management, Point of Sale, Supplier, Description:

Accounts, Items e.t.c. This project is still in under development and currently integrating an open source

ERP with the system .

MVC 5.0 , EF , Code First , SQL server , Repository Pattern , Unity of Work , Linq Query , WPF , Web Api , Technologies:

ERPNext (an open source python base ERP Solution)

Responsibilities: Fetching Data from Attendance machine and making Employee Payroll, Reporting and Time sheets

5. Access Control System Automation (ZKTeco)

Desktop application to fetch the data from biometric machine and upload the data in chunks to the remote Description:

server. Application iterate after the user define time and fetch the data in repetition mode .Data include Face images, check-in, check-out date time, roles, password via SDK and API. The following devices have been

setup and programmed so far

 Suprema ZKTeco

• Portable Biometric Attendance Machine

WPF, maha app controls (3rd party WPF controls), ASync Await, MVVM, Task Factory parallel library (TPL), Technologies:

XAML, Com programming, compact DB, SQLite, blend tools

Responsibilities: Complete Project development and deployment.

URL:

6. BOMS (Saudi Telecom Company Project KSA)

Description: Business object management system specially designed for Saudi telecom company to manage its complain

> system. Client can assign complain in the form of ticket to either contractor or the sub-contractor. In each party we have the admin, coordinator, supervisor, technician roles to complete the job and make sure the job done according to the standard. Internal chat application is also helpful in coordinating different parties.

Technologies: MVC 5.0, Database first, Sql server 2012,C#,,Entity frame work, SignalR for Chat, JQuery Charts

Responsibilities: Complete Project development and deployment.

URL: http://www.bomsys.com/

HR Management System (USA based product)

Description: Human Resources Management System that allows employers to track, deliver, and access relevant data at

the click of a mouse. Employers can distribute company documents, benefits, and update payroll records through a single system, eliminating double entry and fragmented data. HRMS consist of the following main modules . . .

• HR- All Employee Data integrated with payroll.

• Payroll - complete payroll processing service that synchronizes with HRMS, providing a single-entry solution for truly efficient payroll processing.

•Time & Attendance- This Include online time clocks and timesheets, as well as physical time clocks that integrate with our online timesheets.

• Benefit Administration - manage employee benefit programs. Instantly deliver benefits to eligible employees through their online self-service center. Employees can view SPDs, provider directories, payroll deductions, and make their enrollment online. Once an enrollment is made, your employee's carrier applications are automatically generated & consolidated billing reports updated.

Technologies: MVC 5.0,Asp.net, Sql server 2012,C#,,Entity frame work, Repository pattern, Unity of work,CodeFirst

Approach ,Database first,Telerik controls , kando controls for MVC

Responsibilities: Working in the benefit team by managing life event report, benefit wizard, onboarding, creating and

maintaining old as well as new reports as per client requirement via JIRA ticking system. Tickets are created by client and assigned to the concern programmer via zendesk . More than 200 websites to manage. Some

of them are as under

URL: https://www.afa-qa.emcentrix.com

https://www.ppacahelper.com

https://www.alcotthr.net/hris/index.aspx

https://hrppro.net/index.asp
https://americanfidelity.com/

8. IBackoffice (CANADA)

Description:

iBackoffice is a complete web based gas station and super stores management software. It uses internet to replace the obsolete technology most back office programs rely on and make true convenience store automation possible. Everything happens at iBackoffice secure, password-protected web site. Customers can easily maintain their gas stations/super stores if they are even in hundreds. All the reports generated just on clicks. Each CWS (cashier workstation) is monitor by dedicated ip camera, which is helpful in tracking the fraud cases in combine with Journal Report. This project involves the following...

- ibackoffice.net a web application where owner can view each store's data.
- Web service –use to upload the data from store on shift/store close event.
- connector a desktop application
- window service
- IP Camera use to monitor sale transaction like void, refund, paid out, paid-in and help in tracking fraud case.

URL: www.ibackoffice.net/login.aspx

Technologies: ASP.NET 4.0 using C#, SQL Server 2008, AjaxControlTool Kit, Java Script, XML, CSS, HTML, JQuery,

Window Service, Web Service, Connector Application

Responsibilities: Working on Gilbarco Point of sale (http://www.gilbarco.com/us/products/point-sale-pos-systems)

, Web Development, Window Service, Web Service, Connector Application, Msi Setup, Reporting, Charts, Css

9. Disk Doctors (Canada)

Description:

Disk doctor is a data recovery site that is recovering data from failed storage devices since 1991.I have worked on the several pages of the site and to make the dynamic main menu of the site along with the team. I have also developed lonely 10+ micro sites for disk doctors in mvc. Most of the contents on these micro sites are static except few one like review, comments etc.

Technologies: Asp.net, Sql server 2008,C#,MVC 4.0,Entity frame work.

Responsibilities: Analysis, Application Design and development

URL: http://diskdoctors.com

http://www.diskdoctorsdatarecovery.co.uk/

Micro sites URL: http://photorecoverysoftwares.com/

http://www.windowsrecoverysoftwares.com/ http://www.filerecoverysoftwares.com/ http://www.fatrecoverysoftware.com/ http://www.ntfsrecoverysoftwares.com/

10. Disk Doctors (CMS)

Description: A content management system is a web application designed to make it easy for non-technical users to add,

edit and *manage* a website. Last time our goal was to move the old diskdoctors.com from asp.net to mvc. And make its all contents db oriented. To full fill that requirement cms is designed to load and save the web pages and Meta tags in data base .Although after launching the new site in mvc we have to revert back it to old site due to the Google ranking issues. But still this approach is in progress and under maintenance.

Technologies: Sql server 2008, C#, MVC 4.0, Entity frame work. Responsibilities: Analysis, Application Design and development

URL: http://cms.diskdoctors.com/

11. Disk Doctor Cryptor

Description: Disk Doctor Cryptor is use to protect sensitive Files on Usb Flash Drive. This practical program creates a

password-protected folder on your USB flash drive name Vault, so you can share selected files on your drive without exposing your most sensitive ones. This main advantage of this software is to keep the data secure on the flash drive even when the Usb is lost and goes into the wrong hand. This Software compatible with all kind of Usb drives. Once buy then it can be used with any Flash Drive. License key only valid for One Flash

Drive.

Technologies: C# window form, XML, Files Encryption/decryption. Responsibilities: Analysis, Application Design and development

URL:

12. Disk Doctor Secure Login

Description: Disk Doctor Secure Login is a password management and web form filling program that automates password

entering and form filling. It is available for Google Chrome Extension only at this time. All the Use data is store on either on user's drop box or on the pc in encrypted form. Highly secure and easy to use. Basic idea is this, the extension in the browser communication with the native application (desktop

application). Extension fetch the login detail from the browser on successful login and passes it to the native application. Native application is responsible for storing the credentials either on pc or on users drop box account. Users can also take the backup. Disk Doctor secure Login is the one password you'll need to remember. This password will encrypt and secure all of your data. We don't store your Master Password

anywhere, if your forget it then you can recover it through your email address.

Technologies: JQuery, Javascript, C#, window form, Google Chrome Developer API, QT C++

Responsibilities: Analysis, Application Design and development

Cross Platform: work on windows, Mac and Linux

13. My Well Being Network (Canada)

Description: mywellbeingnetwork is web based application dealing in health sector designed to enable user/client to find

personal trainers, personal chefs, acupuncturists, massage therapists, yoga instructors and practitioners of mindfulness. Each vendor has been vetted by members of the Sam Diego medical community and provides the highest level of service. Clients also may have the convenience of scheduling and paying for services through the site. Payment done through credit card (visa/master card/American express) via Authorized.net

payment gateway.

Technologies: MVC 4.0, SQL Server 2012, Visual Studio 2013, JQuery, Ajax, JSON, Authorized.net

Responsibilities: Application Design and development, Query Optimization

Reference

Will be provided on Demand